Abed El Razzak Chreim

Software Developer

₱ abedelrazzak-portfolio.com

SUMMARY

Software Developer with a Mechatronics degree and industrial experience at Sibline Cement Plant in Automation & Reliability achieving an excellent grade. Gained experience at Way2Go Digital as a Full Stack Web Developer, contributing to four projects. Completed seven freelance projects, including e-commerce sites and payment gateway integrations.

EXPERIENCE

Automation & Reliability Intern

Ciment de Sibline June 2024 – September 2024 Grade: Excellent

- Gained hands-on experience in cement manufacturing, automation (PLCs, SCADA, HMIs), and key machinery (kilns, roller mills, ball mills).
- Secured the HMI network (29 HMIs) as a personal project to ensure continuity in case of failure.
- Downgraded and extracted *mer file to prepare Allen Bradley HMI 2711P-T6M20D as a reserve for 2711P-T6M20D8.
- Organized datasheets for all HMIs into individual files.
- Created an Excel sheet documenting HMI details, software, lifecycle, and connectivity.
- Developed tutorials for HMI management, including upload/download, remote access, and restoring *mer files.
- · Compiled a report on HMI quantities, challenges, solutions, and potential risks.

Full Stack Web Developer

Way2Go Digital July 2023 - November 2023

- Worked within a team of 4 developers on 3 projects using ReactJS, php and WordPress.
- Built business, e-commerce websites and maintained other premade websites.
- Built Restful APIs: Database communication and Blom Bank Cybersource payment gateway.

Sin el Fil

Full Stack Web Developer Intern

Way2Go Digital June 2023 – July 2023 Sin el Fil

- Worked within a team of 4 developers on an e-commerce project, using REACTJS and PHP.
- Built Restful APIs: Database communication.

Full Stack Web Developer Freelancer

Self Employed December 2023 - Present Kraytem

- Completed 7 projects using WordPress, JavaScript, PHP, and CSS.
- Built Payment Gateway RESTful APIs for Blom Bank, Areeba, Wish and Credit Bank Netcommerce.

Professional Projects

1. Fleurielb	Wordpress, JS, CSS	https://www.fleurielb.com/
2. MUC Academy	Wordpress, JS, CSS	https://academy.muc.edu.lb/
3. Vresso Casa	ReactJS, Tailwind CSS, PHP	https://vressocasa.com/
4. Hafnutrition	Wordpress, JS, CSS	https://hafnutrition.com/
5. Mega Brands	PHP Laravel	https://megabrandsoutlet.net/
6. ICC Energy	Wordpress, JS, CSS	https://icc.energy/
7. Vitto	PHP Laravel	https://vittoonline.com/
8. Adopt a Cedar	PHP Laravel	https://www.adoptacedar.org/
9. Dentrooper 360	Wordpress, JS, CSS	https://dentrooper360.com/
10. Navigate Success	Wordpress, JS, CSS	https://navigate-success.com/
11. Premier Arc	Wordpress, JS, CSS	https://premier-arc.com/



EDUCATION

Matn University College (MUC) Bachelor in Mechatronics Technology GPA: 3.3

La providence des Filles de la Charité de Saint Vincent de Paul High School

LANGUAGES

English	 C2
French	 C1
Arabic	 Native

SKILLS

Frontend Developement

JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, tailwind css, ReactJS, Wordpress

Restful API Development & Database

Python, PHP Laravel, Firebase

HMI Runtime/Buildtime Development Software

Allen Bradley, Haver & Boecker, Siemens, Beijer

Online Payment Gateways Integration

Blom Bank Cybersource, Areeba Payment Gateway, Credit Bank Netcommerce, Wish

Graphic Design

Figma, Blender

AWARDS

- · MUC university's Honors list
- · 3rd place Beirut drawing contest

